

THRUPTHI ANN JOHN

PROFILE

I am a Ph.D. student under Prof. C V Jawahar and Prof. Vineeth N Balasubramanian. I belong to the Computer Vision and Information Technology Lab (CVIT) in IIIT Hyderabad. My research interests are in computer vision, machine learning and pattern recognition, especially deep face algorithms.

CONTACT

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/thrupthi-ann-john/

WEBPAGE:

https:/thrupthiann.github.io

EMAIL:

thrupthi.ann@research.iiit.ac.in

AWARDS

Recipient of the Visvesvaraya PhD Scheme for Electronics and IT stipend.

Won third place in Artificial Intelligence Hackathon at Garage Artificial Intelligence Network Summit conducted by Microsoft Garage India in association with T-Hub and MUST Research Club, along with Aditya Arun.

HOBBIES

Art • Music • Reading

PUBLICATIONS AND PATENTS

Thrupthi Ann John, Isha Dua, Vineeth N Balasubramanian, C. V. Jawahar. "ETL: Efficient Transfer Learning for Face Tasks", VISAPP 2022

Thrupthi Ann John, Vineeth N Balasubramanian, C V Jawahar. "Canonical Saliency Maps: Decoding Deep Face Models." T-BIOM 2021.

Patent filed: System and Method for Generating Gaze Mapping Dataset and Predicting Gaze Point on Environment. Inventors: C V Jawahar, Isha Dua, Thrupthi Ann John

Isha Dua, Thrupthi Ann John, Riya Gupta, C V Jawahar **"DGAZE: Driver Gaze Mapping on Road"**, IROS 2020,

TEACHING ACTIVITIES

- Content creation and TA for Foundations in Modern Machine Learning course by iHub and CVIT
- Lab on Generative Adversarial Networks for CVIT Computer Vision Summer School 2017
- Lab on Generative Adversarial Networks for CVIT Machine Learning Summer School 2017 and 2018

SELECTED PROJECTS

Daredevil

We created a system that turns images from a mobile phone camera to sounds that assists visually impaired people to navigate.

Feature Selection for Instance Retrieval using Sparse Ranking SVMWe formulate bag-of-visual words vocabulary pruning as a convex optimization problem that uses the structure of the vocabulary to enforce group-based sparsity on the vocabulary elements. The decrease in memory enables retrieval on low-powered devices without

EXPERIENCE

internet access.

Research Assistant

International Institute of Information Technology Hyderabad July 2013 – December 2014

Software Development Engineer in Test

Microsoft June 2011 – June 2013

EDUCATION

PhD Research Scholar

International Institute of Information Technology Hyderabad January 2015 – Present

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

National Institute of Technology Warangal 2007 – 2011

High School, Science

Our Own English High School, Sharjah 1997 – 2007